#### **Thomas Clarke**

### tom@tombclarke.co.uk | linkedin.com/in/tombclarke | tombclarke.co.uk

# **Profile:**

A degree in Computer Science is allowing me to explore my interests and fuel my passion for technology. I am task focused, have a positive attitude and an industrious work ethic, all of which are important for my degree and for the real world of work. I have worked in several different working environments, all of which are giving me new experiences to help build myself and prepare me for my future. I can adapt to new environments quickly and deal with problems effectively.

## **Qualifications:**

Currently studying: University of Birmingham- BSc in Computer Science with a Year in Industry – September 2014 to July 2018

- 1<sup>st</sup> Year Results Year average was 85%: Robotics (100%), Software Engineering (78%), Software Workshop Java (95%), Language and Logic (85%), Web Programming (88%), Foundations of Computer Science (with functional programming in OCaml) (82%), Artificial Intelligence (77%), Information Engineering (73%) and Multimedia Data (70%).
- **2**<sup>nd</sup> **Year Modules**: Software Systems Components, Functional Programming (in Haskell), Professional Computing, Mathematical Techniques for Computer Science, Computational Vision, Modules of Computation, Team Project, Computer Systems and Architecture, C/C++ and Computer Security.

### John Cleveland College - September 2010 to August 2014

- A Levels: Mathematics (A\*), Physics (A), I.C.T. (A), AS History (C), EPQ (A).
- GCSEs: 3 A\*s, 6 As, 1 B and OCR Level 2 National Double Award in I.C.T. (Distinction).

# **Technical Skills:**

- Strong programming in **Java** (good experience with the Eclipse IDE).
- Working knowledge of C# (used in Unity), MATLAB, OCaml, Haskell, HTML, CSS, JavaScript (including jQuery and D3.js), PHP and SQL.
- Experience with designing and creating experimental data visualisations (labs.majestic.com).
- Learning C/C++ in spare time and taking a C/C++ module in Q1 2016.
- Interest in security: member of the university's Hacking Society and taking module in Q1 2016.
- Programming robots using LeJOS.
- Good experience with version control system Git.
- Basic knowledge of Android Development and Visual Basic.

# **Technical Work History:**

- Software Developer, Majestic, July to September 2015: Using various web technologies and utilising D3.js, me and a team of 2 other developers are using the Majestic API to create data visualisations. The work can be seen at <a href="labs.majestic.com">labs.majestic.com</a>. I also represented Majestic at Leeds Hack 2015.
- Web Developer, Hinckley Homeless group, September 2015, Voluntary: I created a new website for Hinckley Homeless Group to replace their original one using an agile approach to development. The website is hinckleyhomeless.com.
- Software Tester, Crane Electronics Ltd., Summer 2014: Exploring and testing a range of products to identify faults or problems and reporting them to the software engineer for revision. The main project was black box testing on an Android based device.

#### **Thomas Clarke**

# tom@tombclarke.co.uk | linkedin.com/in/tombclarke | tombclarke.co.uk

## **Work History:**

- Supervisor (promoted from sales assistant March 2015), Spar, October 2014 to present: Responsibilities include supervising sales assistants, opening, closing and operating the shop, handling money, and handling customer queries.
- Garden Centre Assistant, Woodlands Nursery & Garden Centre, October 2013 to January 2014: Responsibilities involved fast-paced customer service and till working.

### **Achievements and Interests**

- While at Majestic our best project used data on 50,000 Twitter accounts and displayed them
  in a sunburst diagram and I also worked on integrating Twitter into the project. The project
  was received excellently, and they used their trade mark 'Social Explorer' on it as well as
  pushing it out as a headline on their blog and newsletters.
- Being a proactive player in a team competing in the Game Development society's game jams.
- Attending various hackathons:
  - I represented Majestic at Leeds Hack 2015 (<u>leedshack.org</u>) as a sponsor, where I gave
    a short introductory presentation on Majestic, and worked with the attendees on
    using the Majestic API in their projects.
  - BrumHack 2.0 where our team created a fast-paced fighting game in Unity using C# and having to create extra C# programs to run within the game to gather information about various websites using Majestic's API.
- Member of the Computer Science, Games Development, and Hacking societies at university.
- Tutored students in GCSE Computing and A-Level Mathematics.
- I have participated in extra circular activities including:
  - An Extended Project Qualification (EPQ) based on creating an Android Application,
  - A Silver Crest Award based on Astronomy,
  - A v50 volunteering award.
- Bass guitar (achieved Merit at Grade 3).
- Socialising, live music, and travelling.

# **References:**

- University of Birmingham Computer Science:
  - Hamid Dehghani
  - o Tel: +44 (0)121 414 8728
  - o Email: H.Dehghani@cs.bham.ac.uk
- Majestic-12 Ltd:
  - Steve Pitchford
  - o Email: stevep@majesticseo.com